我们回来啦!
We are back!
我们走
Let's go!
糟糕!
Nuts!
再给我一把,黑男孩.
Gimme the Black Beauty.
Alvin, 放松点. 你是全场焦点.
Alvin, take it easy up there. You've got to share the spotlight.
知道的, Dave.
You got it, Dave.
- Dave. - 我是认真的, Alvin. 这个是有关慈善的.
- Dave. - I'm serious, Alvin. This is a charity benefit.
- 这不仅仅是你自己. - Dave，我听不到你说什么 ...
- It's not all about you. - Sorry,Dave. I can't hear you ...
很多歌迷在喊我的名字.
over the thousands of fans screaming my name.
我知道.
I've got  this.
帮我一把.
I need a help, boys.
Alvin 你赶紧从那里下来.
Alvin, will you please get down from there.
我听不到你说什么.
I can't hear you.
- Alvin,我不是开玩笑的. - 什么？
- Alvin, I'm not kidding. - What?
- Dave 小心! - Alviiiiiiiiinnn!!!
- Dave, look out! - Alviiiiiiiiinnn!!!
Oh, Dave. Dave?
这可以减轻疼痛
This should help with the pain.
我想和孩子们说说话.
I wannna talk to my boys.
我刚刚给你打的镇静剂将在一分钟后起效，所以...
I just gave you a sedative that will take effect in about one minute, so...
让它们进来，快点
But, let them in, quickly.
- Dave! - 嘿，伙计，你还活着
- Dave! - You are alive! - Hey guys!
-.那是一个意外，我发誓 -你还好吗
- It was an accident. I swear. - Are you OK?
-真抱歉，Dave - .我还好
- I'm really sorry, Dave. - I'll be fine.
我只是还要呆在这里一段时间
I'm just gonna be stucked here for a while.
在我离开这里之前 我会安排Jackie阿姨和你们呆在一起
And until I get out, I made arrangements for my aunt Jackie to come and stay with you.
谁是Jackie阿姨
Who is Aunt Jackie?
就是在圣诞节给我们邮递美味的爆米花那个
The one who sent us those mail package of  yummy popcorn for Christmas.
- 爆米花Jackie - Seville先生，你没有多少时间了
- Popcorn Jackie. - You don't have much time Mr Seville.
听着， 我想你们都回家去过像正常孩子的生活
Listen, I want you guys to go home and live a normal childhood.
我甚至已经安排了你们上学的事宜
I even made arrangement  for you to go to school.
- 上学？ - 是的，上学
- School? - Yes, school.
Simon,我全部托付给你了
Simon, I'm putting you in charge.
- 你？ -我指望你了
- You are? - I'm counting on you.
Dave，等一下 为什么要交付给他？
Dave, wait a minute.  Why is he in charge?
他指望我了 - Dave,求你了，别死啊
- He's counting on me. - Dave, please, don't die.
他只是睡觉 他刚刚打了镇定剂
He just sleeping. He had a sedative.
噢，镇定剂
Ah, a sedative.
打扰了， 我来这里是来护送花鼠们回家的
Excuse me, I'm here to escort the Chipmunks home.
我们不离开Dave 我就呆在这里了
We are not leaving Dave. I'm putting my paw down on this one.
你过来
You come here.
.我知道了，我会搞掂！那会更加糟糕
I got it! I'll fix it! No, made it worse.
求你了，走吧
Please, please go.
你越是坚持 他就越好不了
More stress you put on persistent the longer will take him to recover.
你太慢了，姥姥
You are too slow, nanny.
你阻止不了我的，没有Dave我哪里也不去 梦信徒，和归国皇后...
You'll never hit me! I'm not going anywhere without Daaa... ...aaaydream believer, and a homecoming queen...
我希望为了你他能在整个飞行途中都不会醒来
I hope for your sake he stays asleep for the entire flight.
也许你应该再给他打一针，以防万一
Maybe you should give him another shot. Just to be sure.
有什么主意让我们找到Jackie？
Any ideas on how we gonna find aunt Jackie?
跟我来
Follow me.
让一下
Excuse me. Sorry.
Excuse me, got you.
看，Jackie，Jackie 爆米花Jackie
- Look, aunt Jackie! Aunt Jackie! - Popcorn Jackie.
过来，亲爱的 我们找到你了
- Oh, come on dears. - Yeah, we got you.
- !爆米花 -谁去送给Theodore
- Popcorn! - Who's sending to Theodore's?
每个人都有份 给我一个拥抱先
Oh, there is a plenty for everyone. Give a hug first.
过来这里，你这个老泰迪熊
Come over here, you old teddy bear.
我不是那么喜欢拥抱
I'm not really much of a hugger.
孩子们，我介绍个人你们认识 这是我的孙子Toby，Toby？
Oh, boys, I want you to meet someone. This is my grandson Toby. Toby?
嗨，我是Theodore.
Hi, I'm Theodore.
- Toby? - 怎么了？
- Toby?! - What, what happened?
- 孩子们 - .噢 嘿 你好我是托比，很高兴见到你
- The boys! - Oh, hey! Hey,how are you? I'm Toby. Nice to meet you.
托比现在和我住在一起 直到他想到他以后要怎么办
Toby is living with me 'til he figures out what he want to do with his life.
现在看来就成天用他的大拇指 哔哔哔
So far that means going beeoo-beeoo-beeoo with his thumbs the all day.
.重要的是我的手指哔-哔-哔 一直保持第一名
For the record goin' beeoo-beeoo-beeoo with my thumbs right now is keeping me in first place, and that's important.
- .Toby拿上包 - 什么包？
- Toby get the bags. - What bags?
- 拿行李 ..噢 行李 对了 让我把那些也带上....
- The lighters. Get the luggages. - Oh, the lug, right. Let me get those...
- Toby! -快刹车，快刹车
- Toby! - Get the brake! Get the brake!
我很好，不用担心
I'm fine.Don't worry!
真抱歉，Jackie阿姨 她还好吗？
I'm so sorry, aunt Jackie. I'm so sorry. Is she goin' to be ok?
别担心我，我会很快回去的
Don't worry about me, I will be home with no time.
我可是不那么肯定
I wouldn't be so sure.
那是一个意外，我发誓
It was an accident, I swear.
在那里 好几次这样了
Been there, done that. Several times.
我在想他现在会照顾我们吗?
I guess he will be taking care of us now?
我坦率的说他肯定会让我们离开的
I'll take frankly foster of five hundred please-outs.
别担心，我完全能做好
Ain't no problem. I can totally do this.
我是说，我以前把我的猫照顾得很好，直到它跑了
I mean, I took care of my cat...  until it ran away.
“逃跑”也许是说难听了点 我想是它想有自己的空间吧
Well, 'ran away' is kind of strong wordin', I think he just wanted his space.
但我还在附近看到过它
I still see him around neighbourhood.
你知道吗，它喜欢用爪子抓我， 这说明我们还是很亲密的
You know, he like hisses and claws at me. but I think that's his way of saying we're still tight, you know.
你们真不用担心这个 我不会和Dave一样的，你们知道，Dave已经离开了
You guys are nothing to worry about, seriously. 'Cause, I'm not gonna be like Dave, you know, Dave is gone.
不在了？
Gone?
不是不在了， 他还没有死，他还活着呢
Not gone, not gone gone. He is not dead. He's very much alive.
他肯定还会回来的 我要把他的房子弄得很温暖等他回来
He completely coming back. I'm just gonna be in his room, keepin' his bed warm.
你做你的事我做我的事 我意思是说你可以当我不存在的
I'll be doin'my thing,you'll be doin' your thing. I mean, you don't need to know that I'm there.
可我们知道你在这儿 这才是关键
We supposed to know that you there, that's the whole idea.
是的，你们知道我在，我只是.... 我不会像这样：我什么都懂，你去做这些，你去做那些
Yeah, ok absolutely. You know that I'm there,I'm just... I'm not gonna be like: I know everything, and you do this, and you do that.
真的
I mean that.
好的 那就这样吧
All right, let's do this.
伙计
Oh, boy!
Theodore我们会很好的
Theodore, we gonna be just fine.
重要的是我们还活着
The important thing is...we're all still alive.
也许做一张 “康复“卡片会让Dave快点好起来
Well, maybe my "Get Well" card will  help Dave to come faster.
我们拿多点闪粉
It needs just a touch more glitter.
那很好 谁饿了？
That should do it. Who's hungry?
我，我 .我们吃东西吧
- Uh, uh me, me! - Let's eat.
Nada，找到什么了吗
Nada. Find anything?
Alvin?这里是美食城吗？
It's a food ghost town in here. Alvin?
嘿，奶酪球在烤箱里
晚餐，来了
Bingo. Dinner, she is  aserved.
嘿，你在干什么？
Hey, what are you doing in here?
奶酪球？
A cheese ball?
给我点时间，很快
Thumb boy, give me a second, real quick.
我现在真的需要集中精神了 我的重量级冠军已经近在咫尺了
Alvin, I really need to focus, right now because I'm one knockout away from my heavy weight title.
我们也能玩吗？
Can we play as well?
你知道，我不想伤害你 你也不想看到任何一个受伤是吧
You know, I don't want to  hurt your feelings, but else you don't want see anyone get hurt and there gonna be fistsufferean flyin'.
我们来玩MONOPOLY吧
We can play monopoly.
我们成天都和Dave玩这个
We play monopoly with Dave all the time.
听起来不错 我们也应该这样
That sounds funny. We should do that sometime right.
.现在，我要回去像蝴蝶蜜蜂一样勤劳工作啦
Now, I got to back and floatin' like a butterfly and stinging like the bee.
.我们不需要Toby，Theodore 你有我们了
Who needs Toby, Theodore, you got us.
是啊，谁需要Toby。伙计们，这边
Yeah, who needs Toby? Boys, right this way.
我想吐
I'm gonna puke.
如果Dave在这里的话他会怎么说呢？
Do you know what Dave would say if he were here right now?
我想一定气到他
But I think it means to come more from the belly.
过来 别吵
Get together. Be cool.
大家好 伙计们，是我
- Helllooooo? - Boys, it's me.
Dave?
我想你接了电话后 应该还没有把房子烧了
Well, I guess since you've answered the phone,  you haven't burned down the house yet.
Dave.请相信我 好吧
- Have a little faith, Dave. - Yes.
救我
Mayday!
怎么了 不要告诉他
- What was that? - Don't stress him out.
噢...是Jackie. .是，她给我们做了5道美味的食物
- Oh, that was... Aunt Jackie. - Yeah, she's making us a tasty five-course meal.
真的？我能和她聊聊吗
Really? Can I talk to her?
她去练习钢管舞了
She's practising her pole dancing.
钢管舞 但是，那谁做的晚餐?到底怎么了？
Pole dancing? But, what happened with making dinner. Guys, what's going on?
Dave.我得挂了 - Alvin我不是开玩笑的
- Gotta go, Dave. - Alvin, I'm not kidding!
快点好哟 - Alviiiiiiiiinnn!!!
- Get better! - Alviiiiiiiiinnn!!!
没人比他做得更好了
Yep, nobody does that better than him.
Toby,.醒醒
Toby, Toby wake up.
- 不好意思 - 没事，怎么了
- Sorry. - No, that's okay. What is it?
- 我做噩梦了 -.噩梦，我最讨厌做恶梦了
- I had a nightmare. - Oh, the nightmares.I hate the nightmares.
梦到什么了
What was it?
我梦到我们不再有家庭了
I dreamt that we didn't have a family anymore.
Theodore, 那不可能的 不会的，你太紧张了
Theodore, that couldn't happen.  No, you guys are tight.
没人会把我们分开
Nothing could ever separate you.
就算老鹰来了也不能
Less like an eagle swooped down from the sky like caw-caaaw!
这从没有发生过 为什么你认为会发生这样的事呢？你知道....
Which couldn't happen ever. Why would you think that ever happened, you know...
老鹰在费城
The Eagles are in Philadelphia.
好梦
Sweet dreams.
- Toby,让它停下来 你在干嘛
- Toby, make it stop. - What are you doing?
这钟有点毛病 关不掉了
There is something wrong with the clock. It won't shut up.
这样我没发睡觉
I can't sleep.
那是因为它是个闹钟
That's the point. It's an alarm clock.
它能让你们早起
It helps you wake up early in the morning.
为什么会有人想要早起？
Why anyone wanna wake up early?
去上学啊，你8点要到那里
For the school, you got to be there by eight.
早上？ 听着，我可不想像你一样早起
- In t疝e morning? - Look, I don't like any others early anything more than you do.
Alvin.但这是我们的事情 你越早到学校，我就能越早回来睡觉
But we are in this together, Alvin. Soon you get to school, soon I get to compound and get back to sleep.
你意思是说你不和我们一起呆在学校？ 是的
- You mean you don't stayin' with us in school? - No, no , no.
我学习造句的日子已经过去了
I've done my time making very much.
不过学校很有趣，是吧? 有趣？我想是吧？
- But school is fun, right? - Fun? Well, i guess Maybe, it's... fun-ish..
嘿，那是我的猫
Hey, it's my cat!
嘿 小家伙 是我 记得吗
Hey kiddy it's me, remember?
我对你很好的啊
I treated you good.
我们到了
There, here we go.
第一天上学玩得开心点 3点左右再来接你们
Enjoy your first day in school. See you around three-ish.
知道了，就像在公园一样
We got it. This got to be a walk in the park.
我害怕
I'm frightening.
嗨，我是Theodore
Hi, I'm Theodore.
老鹰 老鹰来了
- Eagle. - Go eagle!
这可不怎么好玩
That wasn't very fun-ish.
你一定就是新来的了 我是Rubin博士，这里的校长
You must be our new students. I'm Dr Rubin, the principal.
我们是花鼠
And we are the Chipmunks.
是的，我能从你们的外表上看出来
Yeah, that will explain the fur and booshy tales.
跟我来，男士们 男士们？
- Follow me, gentlemen. - Gentlemen?
我们？好的
Oh, us. Right.
还有一分钟的时候 我们还落后两分....
There was a minute left and we were down by two ...
当时我在想：就算我腿断了也不要紧 让我上，我一定能赢...
And I mind couch: I don't care if my leg is broken, put me in, I can win this...
我从没有放弃过
I never get tired of that story.
所以我自己几乎不能站立...
So I hobbled out barely able to stand...
我有提到我的腿断了吗？
Did I mention my leg was broken?
-Ortega女士? -是的
- Mrs. Ortega? - Yes?
祝你好运 谢谢
- Good luck. - Thanks.
男孩们，欢迎来到我们班 我希望你在这里过得快乐
- Well guys, welcome to home room. - Good to be here, I hope.
这个就是教室吗
So this is a classroom?
我喜欢在早上闻奶油的味道
I love the smell of zit cream in the morning.
你好，小姐们
Hello ladies.
嗨，我是Theodore
Hi, I'm Theodore. Hi, I'm Theodore.
他是Theodore...假如你没听见
Yes, he's Theodore in case you missed it.
我是Simon..
And I am Simon.
我是Alvin Seville
My name Seville, Alvin Seville.
迷人的小姐
Enchantée... mademoiselle.
找人量一下他们的身高才行
Somebody's have to knock these guys down to size.
那十分很简单 他们最多只有8英寸高
That should be pretty easy, really. They are only eight inches tall.
我有15辆车 有超过5辆都是众多人喜欢的
I had 15 cars. I mean that's like five more cars than anybody really needs.
我雇了7个女工 拥有湖人队的场边座位
I had seven maids. Courtside seats to the Lakers.
甚至我的女仆们都坐在那儿
Even my maids had courstside seats to the Lakers.
看着我
Now, look at me.
看我 我失去了所有
Look at me. I lost everything.
除了我的尊严 .他们拿不走
Except for my dignity, they can't take that away from me.
.而这一切都是因为他们
And it's all because of them.
咦，有饼干
Oh, hey ...crackers.
现在奔波着 只是祈祷能找到其他会
Now run around, hoping and praying that I could find other animals that can ...
唱歌跳舞的小动物
sing or dance.
等等，你不会唱歌？是吗?
Wait a second, you don't sing, do you?
嘿，这是我的松饼 给我拿回来，你这该死的小老鼠
Hey, hey that's my muffin. Give me my muffin! You dirty rat.
我会抓到你们的
I will get you Chimpmunks.
女孩们，我们得走了
Girls, we have to get out of here.
我看不到
I can't see.
.我的鼻子 那是我的尾巴，不好意思
- My nose. - That's my tail! - Sorry.
挪一下你的屁股 .好，别推我
- Move your ass. - Ok. Stop pushing me.
我们成功了 唷
- We made it. - Jets Records! - Phew!
噢，我的天啊，是他 Ian Hawke
Oh, my gosh. It's him! Ian Hawke!
Hawke先生?
Mr Hawke?
那个声音，我能分辨出来
That voice! I can't get it out of my head!
Mr Hawke?你好
Hello, Mr Hawke?
好像不是做梦，是真的叫我
That not in my head, that's really happening.
你想干嘛 我想自我介绍一下
- What do you want? - We want to introduce ourselves.
是的 我是Brittany，这是我的姐妹Eleanor
That's right. I'm Brittany. And this is my sister Eleanor.
先生，很高兴见到你
Hello, sir. Such a pleasure to meet you!
我是她们的姐妹 Jeanette 尽管有时我感觉起来像Olivia..
And I'm their sister Jeanette.  Although I feel more like an Olivia or sometimes....
不管怎么样，我们是花鼠美眉
Anyway, we are the Chipmunk girls.
我们很荣幸在你面前介绍我们自己
We will be just so honored to have you to represent us.
你让Alvin花鼠们成为大明星
You made Alvin and the Chipmunk stars.
我们也想成为明星
We wanna be stars too, yeah!
和花鼠们一起玩耍
And hangin' out with the Chipmunks.
好了 在我们得到这些之前，告诉我一件事
Ok, now listen before we get all girly and giggly about this, just tell me one thing ...
你们会唱歌吗？
You can sing, right?
停，不是这里
Hang on, not here.
为什么不到我的阁楼办公室去开会
Why not we take this meeting upstairs in my penthouse office?
这太激动了
This is so exciting.
噢，天啊，真令人不敢相信
Oh, my gosh, can you believe it?
我的第一个顶层办公室
My first penthouse office!
噢..好莱坞标志耶
Oh, my... the Hollywood sign!
我想你会喜欢这里的风景的
I thought you might like the view!
女士们，告诉我一些关于你们的事
Ladies, tell me little something about yourselves.
我们在一个 只有300人的小镇里长大的
We grew up in a small town, population 300 and ...
真的？那太棒了
Really? That's fascinating. Great!
好了 现在好好表现吧
All right, impress me!
一.二.三
One, two, three.
女孩们，女孩们，
Girls, girls, girls.
猜一下谁会成为了全世界第一的花鼠组合？
Guess who just became the number one Chipmunks' band in whole dang world?
Ian Hawke.
什么时候我们可以和花鼠们见面
So, when can we meet the Chipmunks?
好问题 答案是...
That's an excellent question  and the excellent answer is...
我已经不再代表Alvin和花鼠们了
I don't really represent Alvin and the Chipmunks anymore.
噢，怎么回事？ 很老套的故事
- Oh, no. Wha-what happened? - Oh, classic tale.
当我见他们的时候很可爱，天真 他们什么也没有，之后
Sweet and innocent when I met them, they had nothing ...and then I work my butt of
.我尽了全力让他们成为了摇滚明星
to make them rock stars and...
后来他们变了 变成坏蛋
They changed. Turned out to be like bad cheese.
.不 多可怕啊
- No. - That's terrible.
我一直把Alvin当成我自己的儿子一样对待
I know. I mean, I treated Alvin like my own son, you know.
而他们就这样离我而去
And he just goes and spits on me.
实际上，我有的只是他们留给我的一脸口水
Literally. He filled his chipmunk's cheeks with saliva and just had at it.
可别让我提起Simon了 幸好不是Theodore
- Don't even get me started about Simon. - But not Theodore, right?
这可爱的还更需要注意
It's the cuddly ones you have to watch for.
为什么我们要谈他们呢 他们已经完蛋了，被解雇了..
But why we are talkin' about them for, c'mon? They are over, fired, nobledeu疝e (noble death)...
花鼠们的蠢说法
Chipmunks' stupid sayin'.
.不过...
But ...
笨女鼠们，请系好安全带
Girl Chipmunks' stupid sayin' ... Fasten your seat belts!
我看着的他眼睛说，Jay，Beyonce在哪里？
So I eyed Jay Z's eyes right, and I said:  Jay, where is Beyonce?
然后他说：她正拿着一碟子的 奶酪球...，我一转身
And he says : She's holding a plate  full of cheese balls, turn around ...
猜是什么
And guess what..
还真是她 Dave让我看着他们
- She was. - PS, Dave left me in charge.
我们每天晚上会呆到10点
We stay up to ten every night.
.看看我能做些什么
Look what I can do.
你真是Theadorable
You're Theadorable.
不好意思 没事，没有伤到我
- I am so sorry. - That's cool. No harm done.
还没完 女孩们，我想和他们私聊下
Not yet. Girls, please, private conference.
谢谢
Thank you.
听着，摇滚明星
Listen up, rock stars.
如果你们再敢和那些女孩子聊天 你们就死定了
If you talk to those girls again you're dead.
如果你们再看那些女孩子一眼 你们就死定了
If you look at those girls again you're dead.
如果你们再敢想想那些女孩儿.....
If you even think about those girls...
你有想她们吗？ 有啊，我现在想着她们
- Are you thinking about them? - Well, I am now.
好 你完蛋了
- That's it. - You are dead!
抓住他，砸死你，该死的
Get them, c'mon! Crack you, you dirty rats!
散开
Scatter!
那边，这边 我在跑
- That way. Over there! - I'm runin'.
嘿，笨蛋 有本事就来抓我
Hey Dumbo, catch me if you can.
你死定了 没有
- You are dead! - Not!
加时吧
It's stretching time!
天啊
Oh, boy.
老鹰
Eagle.
老鹰，老鹰 抓住他
- Eagle! Eagle! - Get him.
快！快！ 这边
- Move! Move! - This way.
.抓到你了 .等等..出来
- Gotcha. - Wait, wait, come up...
.漩涡来了 C'mon 这可不太......
- It's swirley time. - C'mon, c'mon guys, this is not so...
求你了，求你了
Please, please!
有让你好看的 谢谢
- That's a good look for you! - Thank you.
我不会游泳 帮帮我 抓住Simon
- I can't swim. Help. - Grab on Simon!
还好吗？
You okay?
恩，还好，你刚刚把我从马桶里救了出来
Well, uh, considering that you just saved me  from drowning in a toilet...
我嘛，很好
I'm, uh, pretty good.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
Alvin, Alvin!  我们不要用暴力解决
Alvin, Alvin!  We're not gonna solve anything with violence!
这是条肥老鼠 闭嘴
- It's the fatty ratty. - Cut it out!
这老鼠一定在树干里堆了很多垃圾 是啊，那么多脂肪
- This rat has serious junk in the trunk. - Yeah, little fatty.
Simon这样会不会让我的臀部看起来小一点
Simon, does this make my butt look smaller?
你的臀部看起来很好了 那些小子只是一群笨蛋
Theodore, your butt looks fine. Those guys are just some jerks.
你威胁他们说要在他们体内建巢？
You threatened to climb inside of him and build a nest.
有点过分了而且甚至事实上也不太可能
That was out of line and not even sure that is physically impossible.
我应该将你们三个停职 可以
- I should suspend all three of you. - Please do.
我还有更好的主意
Instead I have the better idea.
由于预算的削减 我们的音乐规划可能会受到影响
Due to budget cutbacks , we are in jeopardy of loosing our beloved music program.
太可怕了 我知道
- That's awful. - I know.
但是，我还是有一个小小的希望
But, there is one small ray of hope.
这里每年都会举办一个音乐比赛
Every year the District sponsors a music competition...
.赢家将会得到25，000美金
And the winner school receives 25,000 dolars.
如果我们赢了，我们便可以拯救我们的音乐计划
I疝 we win, we can save our program.
你想我们去表演
And you want us to perform?
我在想你到底是不是我们的歌迷了呢
I begin to think that you are a fan?
你们可以考虑一下
Why don't you sleep on it.
等等 好极了
- Wait. - Great.
答应我什么也不要说出去
Promise me that you won't say anything.
校长一定会赞成的 如果让Mr Fencle发现了可...
The principal has a certain image to uphold. If Mr Fencle ever finds out about this ta...
我真是不敢相信你们就坐在我的办公室里 我有你们全部的CD唱片
I just can't believe this, that you are actually sitting in my office. I have all of your CDs.
我甚至到丹佛去看过你们 所以我有这个
I even went to see you last year in Denver. That's where I got this.
那是我的生日 但是我就像.... 花鼠们
It was my birthday. And I was like...Oh, the Chipmunks!
所以，如何？ 你们会代表我们学校出演吗
So, what you say?  Will you represent our school?
实话说，听起来挺不错的
Honestly suspension sounds pretty good to me.
Alvin? 一个对所有，还是3对一
Come on Alvin? One for all, and three for one.
Theodore 精辟，非常精辟 把我们算上
Well put, Theodore.Very well put. Count us in.
飞吧老鹰
Go Eagles!
老鹰，在哪里？
Eagles? Where?
阁楼轿车
Ah, the penthouse limo.
真独特
Très exclusivo.
那个不是Chihuahua吗 电影上那个
Hey, isn't that that Chihuahua? Ya know, from the movie?
嗯，是，当然是他 很多大牌住在这里
Uh, yeah, yeah. I mean, of course it is. Yeah, a lot of big names live here.
- Oh. Como esta? 我一要他的签名
- Oh. Como esta? - I must have his autograph!
噢 噢 Brittany 你想成为明星，想要表现得像个明星
Whoa, whoa, Brittany. You wanna be a star, act like a star.
你不需要他们的签名，而是你签名给他们 噢，好的
- You don't get autographs, you give 'em. - Oh, right.
嘿，看那边，Jonas兄弟
Hey, look over there, there's a couple of the Jonas Brothers.
在哪里？我看不到 到了
- Where? I don't see them. - Here we are.
快去我房间
Ok, let's scootin' to my apartment ...
噢，该死的
What? Did I... Oh, darn it! Darn it to heck!
什么？怎么了？ 女孩们，真不好意思..
- What? What's wrong? - Girls, I apologise but ...
我好像把钥匙留在办公室了
I seem to left my keys back in my office.
你们其中一个能钻进去从里面把门打开吗
What if one of you shroud through that mail slot and open it up for me from the inside?
我来
I'll do it.
我卡住了
I'm stuck.
好，我帮你，我帮你
All right, I got you, I got you!
不会很难啊
Not so hard.
不要你来了
I wanna lay off the nuts.
好，你来试下，眼镜？ 你身材比较好，还是你去吧
All right, how about you, glasses?  You are in better shape. Wanna go?
.我不太擅长做这个... 我来
- Well I'm not that good in things like this. - I got it!
漂亮
Impressive!
哇奥.
Gee, Willakers!
好极了，瞧，有史以来最好的树屋子
Great. Bingo! This is the best treehouse ever!
红色的钢琴
A red piano.
我们是在做梦吗？ 跟我来
- Is this a dream? - Stand by and catch me.
这比树屋强得多了啊 我喜欢这里的景色
- It's much better than a tree! - I just adore a penthouse view!
不错 Hawke
Nice one, Hawke.
喜欢吗 当然
- You like it? - Sure, Ian.
我住在这里 这里太漂亮了
- I live here. - It's so beautiful.
上一次我们来狐B庄园的时候....
The last time we visited Meerkat Manor ...
有个来的团叫指挥官的....
Arrival group called the Commanders ...
在Whiskers弄了个大型的室内活动
was making large indoors in to the Whiskers' teritory.
Toby, 这太杂乱了 真恶心
Toby, I thought i was messy,  but this is really disgusting.
感觉就像生活在垃圾堆一样
I feel like livin' in a dumpster.
Simon这是狐B庄园，过来一起看
Simon, it's Meerkat Manor on it. Watch with me.
你说对了 我是神经过敏了点
You're right. I thik I'll relax, feelin' my nerves little bit...
这是什么
What is this?
一定是在开玩笑，玉米卷?
You got to be joking? A taco.
竟然在毯子里面Toby!
In a blanket? Toby!
先生女士们 Tobster 准备发球
Ladies and gentlemen, goin' for his turkey is the Tobster.
.加油
Come on baby.
容易得很 我，学着点，朋友们
No problem. Watch and learn, my friends.
哎呀，电视坏了，我想时候玩我的第二喜爱的游戏了
Oops, broken TV, I think this is the time to play my second favorite game.
把烂电视藏起来 你想玩吗？
Hide the broken TV from Dave. You wanna play?
不 对他别那么严厉
- No!!! - Go easy on him, Taco Boy.
今天已经够糟糕的了
This day has been bad enough already.
噢噢，我知道怎么回事了
Oh, I think I see what's going on.
你们几个家伙在学校惹事了是不？ 不，不是的
- You guys are having some problems at school. - No, not really ...
除非你认为 被扔下马桶去也是个问题的话...
Unless you consider, having your head  dumped in public toilet, a problem ...
那么糟糕
Squirrelees are the worst.
至少，我听到是这样的
At least, that's what I heard.
因为，靠我自己不可能知道这些
Because, there is no way that I possibly know that, on a personal level.
Toby,你觉得学校怎么样
Toby, what was school like for you?
- Toby? Tobyyy!!! 什么？
- Toby? Tobyyy!!! - What?
觉得学校怎么样？一个词？
What was school like for me? In a word?
棒极了 你知道 那是因为我太
Awesome! But, you know that 'cause I was like ...
受欢迎了
Extremely popular.
这就是你和你奶奶一块住的原因了吧 已Tobster自居？
- Is that why you are still live with your grandmother? - And refer to yourself as Tobster?
就只会整天哔..哔..哔
And go peeoo-peeoo-peeoo all day?
该睡觉了
Bed time.
Alvin! Alvin醒醒，把闹钟关掉
Alvin! Alvin wake up and turn off the alarm.
Alvin 我没开玩笑 没开玩笑 快关掉它
Alvin, I'm not kidding. I'm not kidding, buddy, turn it off!
伙计们
Guys, guys ...
小伙子们 这可不好笑
Boys, this isn't funny.
你好，我需要你的帮助
Hello? I need help.
有个人抓住了我们 他想带我们去个地方
A man got us. He wants to take us to eternal place.
上学 发发慈悲吧
- School. - Howgh!  - Have a heart.
发发慈悲吧 Dave想让你们去上学 你们就去吧
Have a heart. Dave wants you to school, so you are goin'.
Toby.不要担心我们三个 我们会很好的
Don't worry about taking us three, Toby. We gonna be all right.
如果很糟糕呢？ 伙计们 快点
- If it hurts? - Guys, come on.
相信我，第二天一定比第一天要好
Trust me, the second day is never as bad as the first.
眼镜，眼镜 你不会用眼睛打人的 对吧
Glasses! Glasses!  You wouldn't hit a guy with glasses, would y...
直捣黄龙
Right in the pancreas.
护士？
Nurse?
C'mon Alvin! 记住5个字，闪，趴，蹲，冲，跑
C'mon, Alvin! Remember the five D's! Dodge, duck, dip, dive, and dodge!
你就是下一个 毛球
You're next, furball.
你和我说话吗？
You talkin' to me? You talkin' to me?
这边只有我一个了，你一定是在跟我说话对吧
I'm the only one here, so you must be talkin' to me.
你看到了吗 哈利路亚！
- Did you see that? - Hallelujah!
.真不敢相信，他接住了 你出局了
Unbelievable, he caught it. You're out, man.
成功接到了
And the tackle made, she got's in.
他接得到 我想是个触地
- He got hands. - I think that's paws actually.
我们球队需要他
We can definitely use him on the team.
嘿，小东西 你想加入足球队吗
Hey, furball, how would you like a spot in疝the football team?
足球队？ 你身手不错
- Football? Moi? - I got to say you're good.
我希望你和我们一起去吃个午饭
I'm gonna let you hangin' out with us at lunch.
就是说，如果你想成为我们其中一员的话
That is, if you wanna be on the team?
不错的建议 - Alvin?
- Interesting proposition. - Alvin?
我考虑好再回复你 只有一次机会
- Maybe I'll get back to you on that. - This is a one-time offer.
不要想太久
Don't take too long and think it over .
好极了，但是我要先搞定我的兄弟们
Great, but I will dish my brothers!
我要成为花鼠历史上的第一个球员
Just to become the first chipmunk ever to  play an actual pose on a football team.
没有机会了
No chance.
球场是公平的
The stadium is unanimous.
出局，出局，他接到了
It stots and goes, it's out, it's out... and he catches it!
观众们疯狂了
The crowd goes crazy.
我
Me?
我想那个超级冷酷的人在叫你
I think that super cool jock table is paging you.
为什么我要去？
Why would I go over there?
听着，我还担心太受欢迎呢
Look, if I really need to worry about being popular.
你好 会说话的花鼠 世界知名摇滚明星
Hello, talking Chipmunk. World-famous rock star ...
伙计们 我还穿这睡衣呢
Dive with his own flesh doll. Guys, I'm on pajamas.
老是自吹
Not to toot my own horn bike.
拜托，这是件愉快的事
Come on, it's delectable.
Alvin.去吧 真的？
- Just go, Alvin. - Really? You really mean it?
是的 谢谢 我很快回来
- Yeah. - Thanks. I'll be right back.
有什么事 怎么了
- What's up, geeks? - What's up, man?
说吧
Bring it.
.我能行
I got it, I got it I...
不
Not.
我觉得他很可爱 我也觉
- I think he's cute. - Me too.
我抛了
Toss.
打给我
Call me.
告诉你，花鼠们已经过时了 我又有新的了
I'm tellin' you, Chipmunks are old news. I got the next big thing.
会唱歌的女花鼠们
Singing female Chipmunks.
为什么女花鼠就得不到他们的肯定
God, what part of singing female chipmunks some of this people do not understand...
女孩们，我们也去学校
Girls, we are goin' to school.
他会上 而且会得分
He's up, and he scores.
嘿，我接到了，为什么不给我来个击掌
Hey, right up, ass? Wow, don't hate on a high five?
好
Yeah, high five.
听着，Alvin，我知道你一直在忙你的球队
Look Alvin, I know you've guys been busy with your sporting gathers and what not...
但我确实需要你回家帮帮我 我无能为力
- But I can really use your help at home. - Oh, no can do.
Ryan将教我怎么找个漂亮女孩子来帮我做作业
Ryan is gonna teach me how  to get pretty girls to do my homework.
Alvin，你答应过Theodore我们会出去约会的
Alvin, you promised Theodore we hang out.
今晚一起看狐B庄园 没有漂亮女孩
We are watching Meerkat Manor tonight. No pretty girls.
我今天没有空 你每天都这么说 Alvin
- Dude, I can't swing it today. - That's what you say every day, Alvin.
不要再要我提醒今天轮到你洗衣服
Not to remind you it's your day to do the laundry.
最好你听爸爸的话 Alvin 你可不想被关禁闭
Better listen to your daddy, Alvin. You don't wanna get grounded?
你要去捡起来吗 你想逼我吗
- Are you going to pick that up? - Are you going to make me?
好， 那让我来教教你怎么捡起来
Au contraire, mon frère! I'm just going to elegantly show you how it's done.
Off the glass. And you call yourself a jar.
他是一个爱开玩笑的人 经常这样
My brother, he's a real jokester. Always do.
再见
I'll see you guys around.
轮到我了 轮到我了
- That's my play. - That's my play.
为什么你总是想在我朋友面前让我难堪
Why are you tryin' to embarrass me in front of my friends?
你开什么玩笑 他们才是应该感到难堪的人
Are you kidding me? They are the ones which should be embarrassed by.
比赛加油 等不及了 第一排的位置
- Good luck with the show, guys. - First row seats. Can't wait!
我们将会唱哪一首歌？
So, which song are we gonna sing?
没压力 不过学校就靠我们了
No pressure, but the whole school is counting on us.
放心，就像Ryan说的：有谁能够打败会唱歌的花鼠们？
Oh, relax! It's like Ryan said:  Who's gonna beat singing chipmunks?
不管怎样，Simon是个做白日梦的
Finally. Oh, Simon is dreamy.
我觉得Theodore好像在看着我 对 我知道
- I think Theodore was looking at me! - Yeah, I know.
你们还记得Ian说过什么了吗 我们不能相信他
But guys remember what Ian said? We can't trust them.
怎么回事？ 我本来不想说的，但是..
- What happened? - I never thought I'd say this but...
粉红色是我最新喜欢的颜色 她的眼镜很迷人
- Pink is my new favourite colour. - Her glasses were quite fetching.
她就像是个迷人绿乳糖
She's like a beautiful green gumdrop.
如果你们想干好 就要集中注意了
If you guys want to do this you got to pay attention.
也许，现在是我们休息一下的好时候 恩，好的，5分钟
- Maybe, this is a good time for us to take a break. - Good call,take five.
她是对的 我们要集中注意力
She's right. We need to focus.
这是为了我的屏幕保护
This is for my screen saver.
嘿 Buzz 嘿 伙计们 准备好了吗
- Hey buzz! - Hey guys? Are you guys ready to go?
我在家还有很重要的事要做
'Cause I've got a lot of important staff  to do at home.
你一定是他们的监护人了？ .天啊，是的，我是
- You must be their guardian? - God, that I am. Yes I am.
你好Dr,Rubin ， 我以前也在这学校念过书
Hi. How are you, Dr Rubin? I know that because I went to school here a few years ago.
不知道你是否还记得我 Toby应该是不记得了
I don't know if you remember me, Toby Seville probably not...
Toby？嗨，是你，没有带牙套了？
Toby? No way? Hi! Hey, no braces.
好看多了 我把..
- I think it's great. - I did ...
.我把牙套解了，因为...
I did get the braces off,'cause they were just...
我认识一个男孩子也是打鼓的 孩子们，我在车上等你们
I know a guy who actually works on drum heads. I'll be in the car, guys.
有人爱上谁了
Somebody is in love.
我们将替代所有的东西 花鼠们的地位
We are going to replace everything. Chipmunks' honor.
The old false modestly suck up routine.
我想我闻到了花鼠的味道 Hawke先生 有什么可以帮到你..
- I thought I smelled a rat. - May I help you Mr Hawke?
我在想也许我能帮助你们 我刚刚听说了你们的音乐比赛
I was wondering if I could help you, Ijust heard about your musical competition ...
我就尽快到这里来推荐我的孩子们
and I just get down here as quickly as I could                                                                         to volunteer my girls.
谢谢你的周到 不过我已经做了决定了
That's very thoughtful of you, but I've already made up my mind.
也许这会让你改变决定的
Perhaps this will change your mind.
女孩们
Girls.
她们和Ian在一起？
They are with Ian?
一二，一二
One, two, one, two ...
她们太棒了
They're astounding.
朋友们，你们刚刚看的是女鼠们
Good people of West Eastman, you have  just witnessed the debut...
的首次亮相...
Of the Chipettes!
谢谢
Thank you!
怎么样？ 她们太了不起了，但就像我以前说的
- Well? - They were splendid. But as I said before...
我已经下了决定了
I have made my decision.
我知道了 你已经做决定了
I see. You've made your decision.
我不需要说服一个学校老师 真正意义上的民主
I don't need to speak out of school doctor,  but in the true spirit of democracy ...
是我们伟大国家的根基
which our great wonderful country was founded upon...
我想说，让人们投票决定吧
I say, l疝t the people vote.
让他们来选择 一人之投一票，让他们决定
Let them choose. One person, one vote, I say, let us vote!
.投票
Let us vote.
投票
Please don't be a flasher granby...
让她们唱
let them sing.
投票
Let us vote.
你很有说服力， Hawke先生
You make a persuasive case, Mr Hawke.
好，这就是我将要做的
All right, here is what I'm going to do.
本周五，每队将在学生面前表演一首歌
This friday, each group will perform one song in front of the student body.
谁获得最多掌声，那么 谁就代表我们学校
Whoever gets the most applause, well, will represent the school.
什么？
What?
谢谢，我们成功了
Thank you. We made it.
我们像大型金刚一样强
Oh, it is on, like Donkey Kong!
狐蒙聚在一起结束了戏剧性的一天
The Meerkats huddle together, at the end of a dramatic day ...
重申了他们的家族观念
to reaffirm their family bond.
Whiskers将比以往更加依赖彼此
The whiskers are going to have to rely on each other more than ever.
伙计们，真开心每天放学后 Ortega女士 能帮我们排练
Guys, I'm so happy that Mrs Ortega can rehearsal with us every day after school.
啊？每一天？ 停一下
- Wow! Every day? - Stop right there, ok!
我们是一个团队，我们需要你
We are the team, we need you.
你可以放松点吗？我们是不会输的
Would you relax? We are not going to lose.
我们明天早上再谈这个
We'll talk about this in the morning.
没什么好谈的 .那排练上见
Not much to talk about. I will see you at the rehearsal.
别抱了 -我没有抱
- Stop huggin'. - I am not huggin'.
你或许也想成为真正的障碍面朝那边，因为你确实在抱
You might as well be really obstacles  in the face countryside because you are in fact huggin'.
我没有 我看到了 而且....
- I'm not. - I saw, and saw...
今晚我睡我自己的床
I think I will sleep in my own bed tonight.
你知道我的，我很高兴我不是蒙狐
You know for me, I'm so glad I'm not a meerkat.
噢，是吗？那是为什么呢？ 我就不用和你拥抱了
- Oh, really? And why is that? - I would never hug with you!
Toby，我可以和你一起睡吗
Toby, can I sleep with you?
什么 对我温柔点
- What? - Be kind to me.
我兄弟在吵架
My brothers are fighting.
什么？ 恩，好的
What? Geeeee... ok.
啊，烤箱？
Man, Dutch Oven!
别是烤箱啊 除了烤箱都行，我不能呼吸了
Not the Dutch Oven! Anything but the Dutch Oven! I can’t breath!
太晚了 烧起来了 烧起来了
It's to late! It burns! It burns!
噢，我来看看，我还有心情做什么
Now, let's see. What else am I in the mood for?
听下我意见怎么样
How about a side order of friendly advice, courtesy of me?
不，谢谢
No, thanks.
Grapes,等下
Grapes, please.
不好意思 Ahem 我是...想让你警惕一下Ian
Heh, heh. Excuse me. Ahem.  So, uh, well, I, I, I just wanted to warn you... about Ian.
什么？
What?
你应该感谢他 他做的一切都是为了你，而Alvin你却伤了他的心
You should be grateful to him.  He did everything for you, Alvin, and you broke his heart.
噢 真的吗 那我怎么做得更大度一点
Hmm,really. How do I put this gently!
他是个坏人 他没心没肺的
He's the devil,  he doesn't have a heart,
比如说他就曾把我们关在笼子里
and one of the things he did for us  was put us in a cage!
Alvin，他不可能做这个 是，想想 你曾在那儿，我忘了.....
- Oh, Alvin, he would never do that. - Yeah, guess, you were there, I forgot...
.你最好小心一点 我不需要你的任何建议
- You, you'd better watch out. - I don't need any advice from you.
不过.. 不过，没什么，Alvin，Ian会让我们成为大明星
-But... -But, nothing, Alvin! Ian's taking us straight to the tooooooopppp!
好，成为大明星，我知道了
Right, straight to the top. I got it.
是，真有趣
Yeah, funny. Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
哈哈哈，我们就要把花鼠们击退
Hah, hah we are, so, going to destroy those Chipmunks!
我不想把他们毁了 我也是，我想和他们一起出去
- I don't want to destroy them. - Me neither. I just want to hang out with them.
好吧 如果你们这么想......
All right, look. If you feel that way ...
也许我们应该退出比赛 什么？
- Maybe we should just withdraw from the contest. - What?!
我会把你们用联邦快递寄回你们来的地方的
I'll put you all in Fedex package and mail you back to whatever tree you came from.
听起来不错吧？，好 开始
Sounds good? Ok then. Take room from the top. Let's go!
嘿嘿，停 穿绿色衣服的矮子.....
Wow, wow stop. Short one in a green dress...
你叫什么名字？ - Eleanor.
- what's your name again? - Eleanor.
好吧 我都看不见你了 你一向来是很矮的是吧？
Yeah, look. I'm losin' you there, you know. Have you always been that short?
我想是的 那应该做点什么？
- I guess. - You've got to work on that.
好的，那我试试这个
Ok, all right. Let me try somethin' here.
Brittany过来，过来这里 不，你们两个退后点
Brittany, here. Come up here. No, you two stay back.
再远一点
A little further.
噢 好，现在可以了
Oh, yeah! Now that I like!
因为 Brittany比你们两更像 超级巨星
It's not just because Brittany is more  than mega-ultra superstar than you guys.
很好，很好， 再分开一点点。Brittany,你呆在那儿
Good, good. Ok, you know what, let's get a  little more separation. Brittany, stay there.
再和她们分开点 给她一点空间，孩子们
Get a little more separation from you guys.  Give her some room! Give her some room, guys.
好了，看着我
All right. Watch me now.
一，二，三 看着我
One, two, three ... Watch me. Watch me now.
你好 - Toby?
- Hello? - Toby?
你在房子里干什么？  Jacky阿姨在哪里？
What are you doing in the house? Where is Aunt Jacky?
Dave 嘿 Dave 发生什么事了
Dave, hey Dave, what's happenin'?
Jacky阿姨在医院
Aunt Jacky is in the hospital.
我有点担心 谁照看孩子们啊？
I am a little worried. Who's watcin' the boys?
我
I am.
Dave 巴黎怎么样啊？ 等等，孩子们还乖吗
- So, Dave, how is Paris? - Wait, are the boys behaving?
当然很好，这里还是天黑呢
Absolutely. They've been just pitchy.
Toby,到底怎了啊？ 没事，别担心
- Toby, what's going on? - Nothing. Don't even worry about it.
你知道吗，我知道你压力太大了
You know, I know that you're not suppose to be stress down.
我现在要走了，这边一切都好 再见 - Toby? Toby?
-So I'm gonna go right now, but it's all good here. Come home soon. Bye. - Toby? Toby?
护士，把我弄出去
Nurse, get me out of here!
救命啊
Help...
我不是有意要打断你玩游戏 只是我看到你和Ryan站在了一起当他混乱的时候
I don't mean to interrupt your game but I saw you stand up to Ryan when he littered...
那是需要勇气的 真的？
- That's to guts. - Really?
我们就是寻找这种人 我是Jeremy Smith，学生会的主席
That's the kind of guy we are looking for. Jeremy Smith, Student body president.
你好 国际巨星
- How do you do, I am ... - International recording star ...
还有垃圾管理员 Simon 垃圾管理员？
- And litter monitor Simon Seville. - Litter monitor?
垃圾管理员 这是我们创造的新职位
Litter monitor,  it's a new position that we've created,
去帮助和提高同学们 环保意识
to help raise awareness to the presssing problem  in our society.
我百分之99同意再加1
I agree 99% plus 1.
你会算术
You did the math.
Simon,我知道这是一个很难的请求
Simon, I know this is a lot to ask...
我们在找一个有责任心的人来担任这个好职位
We are lookin' for a take-charge guy who take charge of this very rewarding position.
怎么样？
What do you say?
.打扰一下各位 我有个通知
Excuse me, everybody. Quick announcement. 疝597
我是 Simon,新的垃圾管理员 请把你们的垃圾都扔到垃圾桶里
I'm Simon, I am the Litter monitor. Put your trash in a garbage can. He's out.
.嗨，小姐们 你还没有意识到你的垃圾 已经掉在地板上了吧？...
Hello, ladies. You are probably unaware that you've thrown a racker on the ground, so ...
我们应该管这个叫早晨警告
We gonna just call this morning warning.
继续
Carry on.
好了吗 兄弟们 干嘛
- Right up, dudes? - What up, pal!
嘿，大家看看 这是我们球队的新成员
Hey, everybody! Check it out. The newest member of the football team.
很快就有他的第一场比赛了 伙计们 别惹我
- Soon enough for his first away game. - Guys, don't mess with me.
.我和教练说了 .你加入了
I talked to couch. You are in.
太好了 看看
- That's great. Awesome. - So, check it out, hey man...
我们新的垃圾管理员
We are watchin' the new litter monitor.
我还不知道学校有垃圾管理员
I even wasn't aware that school even had a litter monitor.
别告诉他
It don't but don't tell him that.
你打算捡起来吗 不
- Are you goin' to pick it up? - No.
很遗憾听到你说这个 我想我应该记你的罚款
Well, I'm sorry to hear that,  I guess I'm going to have to, anyway a tuition.
不，垃圾的罚款？
No, I got a suition from littery.
噢 你想跟我玩？ 猜怎么着，我成天都玩这个 - Simon!
Oh, you wanna play that game, do you? Guess what, I can play that game all day long. - Simon!
开开玩笑的
It's a joke, dude.
但是垃圾不是笑话
Litter is no joking matter.
你是个笑话 取笑你的
You're the joke. We are messing with you.
这根本就没有什么垃圾管理员
There is no such a thing as Litter monitor.
什么 大骗子
What? Big liar, huh!
Alvin，你早就知道了？ 兄弟对你来说是什么意思
You knew about this, Alvin? Spelling "brother" mean anything to you?
当然
Yes, of course.
他先在有新的弟兄了 他进球队了
Well, yes he has some new brothers now he is on football team.
你还没有捡起那垃圾
You still hadn't pick up that litter.
你叫我去捡垃圾？
Want me to get rid of litter?
就从你开始 放手，放手
- Let's start with you. - Hey, let go, let go. Noooo!!
触地特分
Touch down.
我等一下再去找你们
I'll catch with you guys in a second.
好，我承认我是个笨蛋
Ok, I'm a total jerk, I admit.
我们没事了吧
So are we cool now?
好吧 已经过去了
Ok, I'm going to put this behind us ...
为了Theodore 好
- For Theodore's sake. - I know.
那是我为什么要给你我的.....
That's why I'm giving you my...
Alvin的资金
The Alvin currency that I will be on that stage Friday night.
等等 为什么你不去？
Wait, wait, wait!  Why woudn't you be there?
因为我有...
Because I had a...
什么？ 我
- What? - I...
你有什么 .一场球赛 我终于说了
- You have a what? - A socker ball game. Now I said it.
足球比赛
A football game.
Simon，Alvin还好吧？ - Theodore. 嗨
- Simon, Alvin is everything alrigt? - Theodore. Hello!
我们很好 我们在玩摔跤而已
Yes, we are fine. Just a little dumpster wrestling.
真是疯了这里 是的
- It's crazy in here. - Right.
不要担心，Theo 一切都会很好
Don't worry Theo, everything is gonna be fine.
- Alvin,别错过演唱比赛 不要担心Simon
- Alvin, do not miss that Sing all. - Don't worry, Simon.
我一定会去的，我保证
I'll be there. I can prove.
非常感谢你们今天的帮忙
Hey guys, thanks so much for helping out today.
"Toys for Tots"是一个不错的组织 今天大家辛苦了
"Toys for Tots" is a really cool organization. So, everybody is gettin' cool points today.
Theodore怎么啦？ 我也不知道
- What's goin' with Theodore? - I have no id疝a.
嘿 Eleanor 你去看看Theodore需要什么帮助吗 - 好
- Hey Eleanor, why don't you see if Theodore needs some help? - Ok.
它们看起来不是那么舒服 我鞋子吗？
- They don't look very comfortable. - My shoes?
确实不舒服 但是Ian说我要尝试变得高一点
- They are not. - But Ian says that I need to work on being higher.
你本来看起来就已经很好了
Well... I think you look great just the way you are.
你这么想？
You do?
嗨，我是Dave Seville 请留言
Hi, you've reached Dave Seville, please leave a message.
嗨, Toby. 我是Julie Ortega，昨天和你说过的一些的
Hi, Toby. This is Julie Ortega, we talked yesterday...
我打电话是想告诉你
a sort of it. Anyway, the reason I'm calling,
我有点担心Theodore 他情绪有点低落最近
is that I am worried about Theodore, he's been acting a little down lately.
我希望你回去周五的“sing all”
I hope you are going to the "Sing All" Friday.
你知道Theodore 需要所有他能得到的帮助
You know in his down,  Theodore needs all the support he can get.
.比赛那天见 希望有机会和你聊聊 再见
So, I'll see you there. I hope we get a chance to talk. Bye.
好了 弟兄们 该你们勇士上场了
Ok, folks. Time to get behind your Warriors...
老鹰队落后5分 比赛还剩下30秒
They are listening Eagles down by five,  with only thirty seconds left on the game.
比赛时间不多了 他需要想想办法了
- Time is running out for the ... - ...He really needs to make a move here or...
比赛结束了 我知道 让我上
This game is over. - I know, put me in.
嘿，让我上
Hey, put me in.
暂停，暂停 老鹰队请求暂停
- Time out, Time out. Time out Eagles
15号只有9秒的时间赢得比赛了
Number 15 got nine seconds to make it to the game.
好的，该是雄起的时候了
All right boys, it's time for the big A.
我要踢到他们头破血流
I'm going to crush them and burn them to pain. The Alvinator is in the house.
你确定？
Are you sure about this?
.我们该使出我们的秘密武器了
Four to ten say that we need to go for the secret weapon.
他说的对 他让我来做决定了
Chip is right. He left decision on me.
.创造历史吧
Time to make history, boys.
我来击败你 Jennifer
I'm taking you down, Jennifer.
是你要失败 老熟脸
You are the one going down, rat face.
我要把你像橘子一样吃掉再
I'm going to crack you like an acorn  and eat you for dinner.
加点蚕豆和红酒
With some fava beans and a nice chianti.
这是关于我老爸吗
Is this something about my father?
..一二
One, two ...
我来了
I'm comin'!
这才是我说的 要恨就恨这场比赛吧
That's what I'm talkin' about. Don't hate the pain, hate the game.
我爱这场打猎 兄弟
I love the hunt, man.
最后得分，老鹰队15，战士队14
Final score: Eagles 15. The Warriors 14
怎么样？傻B
What you think about that, sucker?
这就是我想要的 你们可真是强力鼠
- That's what I'm talking about. - You're really muscle chipmunk.
给我A给我O给我W给我E给我M
Give me a A, give me an O, give me a W, give me an E, give me a M...
怎么说来的..太棒了
How that spell...awesome.
我是国王
I am the king of the world.
我Alvin一起玩去吧
Party with Alvin.
都到海景房去
Everybody to the beach house.
走吧
Let's do it.
我来这里是为了你们
Look guys,  I just want you to know that I'm here for you.
有的是时间 我去找Alvin 所有的事都会解决的
There is plenty of time.I'm gonna go find Alvin. Everything is gonna work out.
谢谢你Toby 女士们先生们，有请Dr Rubin
-Thank you, Toby. Ladies and gentlemen, Dr Rubin
谢谢 学生们 谢谢你们
Thank you, students.Thank you.
欢迎来到我们激动人心的歌唱比赛
就在花鼠和女花鼠们之间的比赛
Between the Chipmunks and the Chipettes.
不过记住 这里没有赢者输者
Remember students, there are no winners or losers.
当我们赢得比赛 记得提醒我通知花鼠们
Remind me to tell the Chipmunks that one, when we blow up off the stage.
有机会作为学校代表赢取25000美金拯救我们的音乐系
...To our school, a chance to win 25 000 dollars to save our music department.
接下来， 请上我们的女花鼠们
So, without further due, I give you ... the Chipettes.
该我们了 美女们 难以置信
This is it girls, can you believe it.
Brittany, 展现自己的机会到了
Brittany, your time to shine baby.
去好好秀给他们瞧瞧 是 我能做到
- Go up there and knock them dead. - Yes sir, I can do it.
你们两个 我只想让你们知道 别挡Brittany的路 好的
- You two I just wanna let you know, not to get in Brittany's way. - Ah, ok.
喜欢你所看到吗 给Ian打电话
You like what you see, call Ian Hawke ...
310-555-5309.
别担心 Alvin很快就回来 Alvin！
Don't worry, Simon, Alvin will walk through that door any minute now. Alvin!
我回来了
I'm back.
谢谢 唱得好，女孩们
- Thank you so much. Thank you. - Well done, ladies.
让我们来拭目像暴风雨一样的花鼠们
And now, let teared for the group that will rock you like a hurricane.
至少就像很多你的学生告诉我的一样
At least that is what many of you students have told me.
欢迎花鼠们
Here they are...the Chipmunks.
嘿 你知道吗 有句话说在团队里没有自我 他们是对的
Hey, you know they say there is no "I" in the word "team", and they are right.
你知道IN是什么吗？Alvin
But,you know where is "IN" ? Alvin.
就是像你们 女孩们
Such to be you.  Girls!
可悲，他是对的
Sadly, he's correct.
找到他了吗 .对不起，我找遍了周围都没有找到
- Did you find him? - Guys, sorry, I searched the whole perimeter.
我也不知道为什么 整个队也没有回来
And I don't know why, but the team is not back yet.
我们怎么办
What should we do?
我应该....
I would ...
我应该叫别人.....但不是我
I would ask someone...who's not me.
.我知道我们应该怎么做
I know what we should do.
嗨，大家好
Hi, everyone.
我兄弟，Alvin今天来不了了
Our brother, Alvin couldn't be here today.
重要的是，我们不会出演的如果Alvin不在
Thing is, we never performed without Alvin ..
我们还没有准备好
and we are not starting now.
你们不能只有两头小猪 你们不能只有两个士兵 所以.....
You can't have two little pigs, you can't have only two musketeers so...
只有我们俩不能唱
You know you can't have only two chipmunks.
谢谢
Thank you.
我带你们回家
I'll take you home.
女孩们，听到了吗
You hear that, girls?
胜利的声音
That...is the sound of success.
.我知道你们的失望
I relize how devastated you...
但是花鼠们也一定有自己的原因
Chipmunks' funs must be...
所以我想这意味着女花鼠赢了..
So I guess that means that the Chipettes...
过来，女孩们
Come on girls, let's take a victory lap.
过来
Hey, come on guys, let's go.
Britt,我们得去
Britt, we have to.
走
Let's go.
谢谢
Thank you.
生活真美好
Life is good.
尤其你不是一个失败者的时候
Especially when you're not a loser.
嘿 伙计们 我在这儿
Hey guys? I'm here.
兄弟们？
Guys?
噢 太棒了
Oh, great.
Alvin.他们走了.
They are gone, Alvin.
他们永远也不会原谅我的 你知道吗 Alvin...
- They never gonna forgive me. - You know ... Alvin...
Ian他是对的 你永远也不会关心其他人除了你自己
Ian wa疝 right. You don't care about anyone except yourself.
噢，顺便说下 我也不想以这种方式赢你
And oh, by the way,  I never wanna to win this way.
Simon,你醒了吗
Simon, are you awake?
Theodore,我不责怪你生气
Theodore, I don't blame you for being mad.
我离家出走了？
I ran away from home?
别去公园找我 我不在那里
Don't look for me in the Zoo, because I'm not there.
不.不 Theodore
Oh, no Theodore ...
你好？
Hello?
狐B家族
Meerkat family?
有人在家吗
Is anyone home?
我是Theodore，我想成为你们的一员
My name is Theodore, I like to be in your family.
也许他们藏起来了
Maybe they are hiding.
别害怕
Don't be afraid.
你不是狐B
You are not a meerkat!
Toby你来找老虎，狮子和熊那边
Toby, you take the lions, the tigers and the bears ...
Simon和我去检查蜜蜂那边
Simon and I will take the butterfly room.
好老鹰
Nice Eagle.
不要动Theodore
Don't move Theodore.
好的
No problem there.
别动 别动小子 我们马上把你就救出去
Hang in there, hang little guy. We'll get you out from there.
我们要定个计划 我们需要定个精密的计划
Ok, we need a plan.  And we need carefuly executed plan.
或者你可以像个疯子一样跑进去
Or you can just ride in there like a maniac.
Theo,.小心
Theo, watch out.
嗨，我是Theodore
Hi, I'm Theodore ...
嘿，大鸟，看这里，你饿了吗 先抓这A
Hey birdy, look up in here, are you hungry? Catch this "A"?
那是开胃菜
That's for appetizer.
放松点 我们出去聊好吗
Let's all just relax, and we talk this out, ok!
听着 我想我知道你为什么想要Theodore 真的
Look, I guess why you want Theodore, I do,
不过 不好意思 我不会允许这事发生的
but I'm sorry, I can't let that happen.
因为他是我的兄弟
He's my brother.
别让他知道 因为最近我真的是个大混蛋
Not let him know that, because I've been a such a big jerk lately.
如果谁是值得被吃掉，那就是我
If anyone deserves to be eaten, it's me.
不是真的
Not really.
Alvin.我来帮你
I got you, Alvin.
当心老鹰
Watch to the eagle.
他们的敌人就是大象 幸好我知道它们在哪里
Their only mortal enemy is a piggy elephant. Luckily I speak a little habitat.
我想这行得通
I think it's working.
天啊，这太大了
Guys, that was huge.
那我们现在是一对所有还是三对一
He's right.Now we are one for all and three for one?
算了吧，拥抱一下
Come on, Simon, hug it out.
你知道的，对不起
You know I'm sorry, Sy.
不要叫我去亲你我可是会的
Sy, don't make me up to kiss you because  I'll do it.
我不介意
I don't care.
过来 终于好了
Here come the lips! The makeout train leaving the station.
最后 我想我想要那个拥抱
I think after all, I'll take that hug.
打Ian Hawke电话
Justine, call Ian Hawke.
310-555-5309.
Morris,让Ian听电话
Morris, get me that Ian Hawke on the phone.
你们在这里
There you are.
我亲爱的挣钱小东西
My sweet little money makers.
记得我曾经和你们说过 我会让你们变成大明星
Do you remember when I told you that I would make you all big stars?
猜猜是谁在斯台普斯中心 为Britney设了场？
Well, guess who's opening up for Britney Spears at Staples Center tonight?
我在做梦吗 天啊
Am I dreamin'? oh, my gosh!
. 等一下，我们不能去 我们不能错过学校的音乐会
Oh, wait, we can't.  We'll miss the school concert!
是的 你们会错过学校的音乐会
That's correct. You will miss the school contest.
你们那么聪明 看来我真的没你们厉害
其实根本就不是为了学校的竞赛 其实一直都只是为了把Brittany弄成明星
It was never about that stupid school contest, it was always about making Brittany a star.
这就是你想要的是吗
That's what you wanted, right?
恩，是的 .今晚是一个很好的机会
- well...yes. - Tonight is your big chance.
Brittany.全部都是为了你
It's all about you, Brittany.
那Jeanette和Eleanor呢
But what about Jeanette and Eleanor?
她们可以助唱 我也会给她们薪水的
They can sing backups, I got them some staff too.
我们可是好姐妹 要么一起唱要么不唱
- We are her sisters. - We either sing together or not at all!
好 我需要的只是Brittany
Ok, fine. All I ever needed is the B-girl.
Ian 如果她们不去我也不去
Ian, I won't do it without them.
好吧，好吧，那就实行B计划
Ok, fine, fine. Let's move on to Plan B.
谁喜欢烧烤？
Ok, who likes barbecue?
我知道有一间非常好的烧烤餐厅 花鼠烤肉做得很棒
Because I know this awesome little barbecue restaurant in the valley,  that makes the best roasted chipmunks.
味道好极了 当然，除非你们唱歌
Real tasty. Unless of course, you wanna sing?
欢迎您的到来.. 和谢谢你们对我们学校音乐的支持
Welcome to West Eastman, and thank you for supporting music in our schools.
记住，获胜的那一组将会为他们 学校赢得25000美金
Now remember,the group you pick tonight, will win 25000 dollars for their school.
现在我们有很多的表演 我们需要在9点半的时候结束
Now there's got a lot of acts, and we have to  trow heat off by nine-thirdy so ..
不用多说，举起双手欢迎我们的橘子女孩儿.....Lou Rosarro
without no further due, representing Orange girl put your hands together for...Lou Rosarro.
我们会再见吗 你也想要分一杯羹吗
We meet again. You wanna a piece of it?
老鹰
Eagle.
Ian Hawke?
我来
I'll take that.
我还没有意识到你现在处于下层社会了
I didn't realise that you are runnin' a low life.
- Alvin, - Brittany? 你们对表演还有兴趣吗
- Alvin, - Brittany? - Aren't you guys still interest?
我今晚不能去表演了
I'm not gonna be able to perform tonight.
那我们的音乐系怎么办？ 学校全靠你们了
What about the music department? The whole school is counting on you.
我知道 但是我不得不听你说关于Ian的
I know, I know. I had to listen to you about Ian.
别告诉我...
Don't tell me...
.是的，他把我们锁在笼子里
Yes, he locked us in a cage.
这就是你们最棒的了吗 我可有权利要求你们使出你们最好的 这可不是你们最好的
This is this the biggest you have? I have a licence to call and asked for the biggest thing, that's not the biggest what you got.
我会把这消息告诉Dr Rubin
I will go and take the news to Dr Rubin.
- Brittany? - Alvin,别动
- Brittany? - Alvin, don't move.
收到 Brittany 我来了
You got it. Brittany, I'm comin' to get you.
Simon,你知道怎么打锁吗？
Simon, how do you know to hit a lock?
收到
Roger that.
我要快点救那些女孩出来
I need to get to those girls. Fast.
我知道
I know how.
.第三个号码是最难解的..
The third number is notoriously the hardest to crack ...
.我只能提供号码，其他的我不会...
I'm assuming that provide number that we can't assume...
.前两个号码是1 我相信是1了
The first two numbers are one. I got to go with one.
打开了
It opened.
太好了 Ian来了
- All right,  girls ... - Ian is coming.
尽快打给我
Put the phone back, hurry!
准备好表演
Get ready to be fabulous.
我们准备好了
We are ready.
你们最好给我准备好 今晚的表演我要拿回我原来拥有的一切
Yeah, you're better be. Because tonight's performance it's gonna put me back on the top.
下面我们欢迎cherisse
And now please welcome...Cherisse.
司机，带我去Arena 贵宾入口
Driver man, take me to the Ar疝na. The VIP entrance.
.尽快 Moonroofs的表演了
Tout de suite. A little moonroofs actions.
Moonroofs上了, moonroofs, roofs, roofs...
Moonroofs are go, moonroofs, roofs, roofs...
香槟
Champagne.
.不介意我喝点吧 .如果我喝了
If you don't mind ... If I do...
知道我为什么要喝吗？ 因为今晚我们就要举杯庆祝
You know why I don't mind if I do? Because tonight we've got to toast ...
一个特别的人，就是我
To a very special someone, named me.
他们说我不可能做到 他们说我永远不能死鱼翻身
They said I couldn't do it,  they said I never bounce back.
猜猜怎么样 .见鬼去吧
Guess what? Time to kiss my ass.
干杯，让全世界把花鼠忘掉
A toast! To the ladies who gonna make the world forget about the Chipmu...
不，你们在干嘛？Alvin
No, no, no, no! What are doin'? Alvin.
嗨 Ian 很高兴见到你，看起来不错
Hi Ian! Good to see you. You look alright!
不，我们已经签了合同的
No, no! I signed a contract.
Jeanette跳，等等 - 我不是太好...
- Jump, Jeanette. -Wait! - I'm not really good...
我打赌你一定没得表演了
I bet it you don't perform.
猜猜Alvin. 你成功了
- Gas, Alvin. - You got it!
Ian，用麦当劳的话说，你被解雇了
Hey, Ian! In the words of McDonald, you're fired!
Alvin有说是什么吗？ 没有Alvin就没有花鼠女孩
- Hey guys, any sayin' about Alvin yet? - No Alvin and no Chipettes.
校长和学校都靠我们了
Just Dr Rubin and the entire school are counting on us.
别担心 一切都会好的
Well, you know...you know don't worry everything will work out...ish.
Alvin!快点 别担心
- Faster Alvin! - Don't worry...
我现在去找我朋友帮忙 等在这儿
I'm gonna get a real help from my friend, stay there.
知道了 Alvin.
Roger that Alvin.
就像我回到了赛场上一样
Just like I'm back on the racetrack.
你去哪儿 想干嘛
Where you going? What are you doing?
等回家后我告诉所有人我救了 Alvin Seville
Wait 'til I tell everybody back home that I've saved Alvin Seville.
我想我还欠你一个Ian的道歉
I think I owe you an apology about Ian.
和Britt在一起 我死定了
Stick with me Britt. I'll never stay alive.
是吗 我真的不该这么做
Oh yeah , I'll never got to do that.
我得说 他真的很坚持
I got to say, he's definitely persistant.
我们得赶紧把他甩掉 坐好了
- We got to lose him. - Hang on.
我数3一起跳上去
I got a plan, jump on a count of three!
Three.
就这样 我畏高
- Oh, that's it. - I didn't like heights.
Jeanette.抓紧了 带女孩来我这里
- Keep your tight Jeanette. - Bring my girls right to me.
我们需要那遥控器 伙计们 我知道应该做什么
- We need a  remote. - Guys, I know what have to do.
脱下Ian的帽子
Hats off on Ian.
遥控器
The remote.
我拿不到
I can't reach it.
我在努力 抓住我的腿
I'm doing it. Hold my ankles.
成功了
I got it.
我成功了？
I got it?
做得好 Jeanette.
- Well done, Jen. - Top work, Jeanette.
Ian, 你大错特错，我们不需要那些
Hey Ian, you were wrong. I don't need these.
再见了  再见 Ian
- Bye bye. - Adios, Ian.
现在，请出我们最后的表演者
And now, for our final act of the night...
听着，还有一秒改变局面 相信你们一定不会失望的
And, listen we have last second change to the line up, but we don't think you gonna be to disapointed.
West Eastman的代表--花鼠
Representing West Eastman it's...the Chipmunks.
Theodore.看来我们得上去了
We may have to go up there , Theodore.
没有花鼠们 我们还得继续
If there are no Chipmunks we gonna have to move on.
我不想再做好人了
I don't wanna be good again.
抱歉了，我们得继续下去
I'm sorry, but we ha疝e to move on.
你们知道我不是花鼠
I'm not a Chipmunk, as you can see.
音乐在哪儿 失败者 音乐在哪里？音乐..
Where is the music you loser? Where is the music? Music?!
好，我唱
Ok, I got to song.
哇，强！
Well, that...was huge.
谢谢
Thank you.
花鼠在这里
The Chipmunks are in the building.
那是花鼠女孩儿 - Alvin.
- It is the Chipettes! - Alvin.
你好， West Eastman.
Hello, West Eastman.
我们下来了 站稳了
I'm puttin' her down. Hang on.
- Alvin. 给我击掌 兄弟
- Alvin. - Give me the high-five, brothers.
女士们先生们West Eastman的代表
Ladies and gentlemen, representing West Eastman  it is my great pleasure...
真荣幸
This is such an honor.
你还是我们 我们
- For you or for us? - For us.
一起来
We get it! Come up, guys.
让我带给你们花鼠女孩儿和花鼠
And now I give you the Chipettes and the Chipmunks.
谢谢
Thank you.
是谁夺得25000美金相信大家已见分晓
Hey everybody, it's clear that we have a winner of the 25000 dollars ...
就是West Eastman
And it's West Eastman High.
我们成功了
Guys, we did it.
这是你的 Dr Rubin.
It's all yours, Dr Rubin.
女士们先生们， 斯台普斯中心非常荣幸欢迎女花鼠们 921
Ladies and Gentlemen, The Staples Center is proud to welcome the Chipettes.
嗨，大家好，我是Jeanette，我是Eleanor
Hi everyone, I'm Jeanette and I am Eleanor.
我是Brittany.
And I'm Brittany.
我们是女花鼠
And we are the Chipettes.
一二三
One, two, three.
- Dave,你在跳舞 你好了，太好了
- Dave, you are dancing. - You are even good, Dave. Yeah!
欢迎回来 想我们吗？
- Welcome home. - So, did you miss us?
我当然想念你们 你们是我的孩子
Of course I missed you. You are my boys.
Dave,你有多想我们? 现在我们是6个了
Ok Dave, just did how much you miss us. There are now six of us.
Alvin, 你说什么
Alvin, what did you say?
女花鼠也需要一个地方住的，是吧？
The Chipettes need a place to cresche , right?
所以我说像你说的 她们想和我们在一起多久都行
So I said that you said, they can stay with us for as long as they needed to.
好， 大家动起来
Ok, this works for Dave. Everybody shake what your mama gave ya!
看看你 准备睡觉去
Look at you. All ready for bed.
看看女花鼠们给你多好影响
Looks like the Chipettes had a good influence.
谢谢Dave
Thanks, Dave.
好，我现在要关灯了
Ok guys now lights out.
各位晚安
Good night everybody.
- Alvin? 我不困
- Alvin? - I'm not tired.
不行，你明天还要去学校
Sorry, but you've got school tomorrow.
不困
Not tired.
Alvin,快点，该睡觉了
Alvin, come on. It's time for bed.
不困
Not tired.
.还不困，不要关灯
Still not tired. More light.
不是开玩笑的 不要关灯
Tired. Just kidding. Much more light.
Alvin,够了  不要让我过去...
Alvin, that's it! Don't make me come over there...
噢.我终于真的累了
Oh boy, I finally got relly, really tired.
晚安 Dave.
Good night, Dave.
Alviiiiiiiiinnn!!!
别走开！后面还有两段精彩的！
谢谢观看
就快到了！最后面还有一段！
好样的，先生们，只有区区10排看台座椅要清理，开始吧
行了，行了，够了伙计
行了，我会离开的，这有必要吗？
别这样，没必要这样…
至少让我回去拿回我的钱包吧